nationalpriorities.org 2017-02-27

# Privacy Policy

Nationalpriorities.org is committed to protecting the privacy and security of visitors to our website. Nationalpriorities.org does not collect personal information when you visit our website unless you choose to provide that information.  Outlined below is the NPP online privacy policy. If you have questions about this policy, [ please let us know ](https://www.nationalpriorities.org/about/contact/).

## At a Glance

  * You can remove yourself from our systems whenever you want.
  * We collect analytics about how people use our tools. We use that information to improve them, and we sometimes share it with reporters, funders and others. But we only share that information at an aggregate level; we never share information about individual users.
  * Our tools sometimes link to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of those sites, and recommend you read their privacy policies for further information.
  * We do our best to provide excellent, reliable and accurate information through our tools and services. But nobody’s perfect, and if you encounter a problem we’d like to hear about it from your bug report, not your lawyer. Everything we publish is offered as-is, without warranty or guarantee.
  * We believe in open source, and we publish things under a variety of open licenses. But we have to protect our branding and trademarks; you shouldn’t use them to imply that your project is affiliated with us unless you’ve gotten our written permission to do so.

## Information Collected and Stored Automatically

When you visit , we may store some or all of the following: the Internet address from which you access nationalpriorities.org, date and time, the Internet address of the website from which you linked to nationalpriorities.org, the name of the file or words you searched, items clicked on a page, and the browser and operating system used.

This information is used to measure the number of visitors to the various sections of our site and identify system performance or problem areas. We also use this information to help us develop the site, analyze patterns of usage, and to make the site more useful. This information is not used for associating search terms or patterns of site navigation with individual users. Nationalpriorities.org periodically deletes its Web logs. On occasion, nationalpriorities.org may provide this information to third party entities it contracts with for the purposes of research analysis.

## Cookies

When you visit some websites, their web servers generate pieces of information known as cookies. Cookies are commonly used to recognize your computer in the future.

Nationalpriorities.org uses persistent cookies to be able to track the number of unique visitors to the site.

Users can choose to disable cookies using their web browsers.  It will not affect their ability to search for, review and retrieve data on the site.

## Personal Information

Users are NOT required to provide any information to search, retrieve, download, filter and otherwise use the data available on nationalpriorities.org.  If you choose to provide us with personal information—like filling out a  Contact us  form with an email address and submitting it to us through the website—we use that information to respond to your message, and to help get you the information you requested. Your email address will not be stored or retrieved by nationalpriorities.org.  Nationalpriorities.org never collects information or creates individual profiles for commercial marketing.

While you must provide an email address and user name for the optional uses of nationalpriorities.org (including our contact form), you should NOT include any other personal information, especially [ Social Security numbers ](http://www.ssa.gov/pubs/10002.html#protect) .

## Moderation of Comments

Nationalpriorities.org enables you to post your opinion on discussion topics. We encourage you to share your thoughts as they relate to the topic being discussed. Your comments will be publicly visible; therefore, the site utilizes a moderation policy to ensure that your comments are appropriate and not harmful to others. We review and moderate comments according to the policy below. The views expressed in comments reflect those of the author and do not necessarily reflect the official views.

We want to publish your comments, but we expect comments generally to be courteous and on the subject matter of this site. To that end, we have established the following policy.

We reserve the discretion not to display comments that:

  * contain obscene, indecent, or profane language;
  * contain threats, or defamatory statements;
  * contain hate speech directed at race, color, sex, sexual orientation, national origin, ethnicity, age, religion, or disability;
  * reveal your own or others’ sensitive/personal information (e.g., Social Security numbers)
  * contain information posted in violation of law, including libel, condoning or encouraging illegal activity, and revealing classified information, or posts that might affect the outcome of ongoing legal proceedings or
  * promote or endorse services or products, including links to external commercial sites. (Note that non-commercial links that are relevant to the topic or another comment are acceptable.)

Do not submit copyrighted, trademarked or other proprietary material in any form unless you clearly indicate that you have permission to do so. By submitting your comments or other work, you grant NPP and anyone viewing the comments irrevocable permission to copy, distribute, make derivatives, display or perform the poster’s work publicly and free-of-charge.

If you are a reporter, please send questions regarding this through normal agency channels rather than by submitting questions here as comments. It is our policy not to post reporter’s questions.

We recognize that the Internet is a 24/7 medium and your comments are welcome at any time. However, given the need to manage resources, we intend to review and moderate comments from 9 am – 5 pm Monday through Friday, except federal holidays. We intend to review and moderate comments submitted at other times as soon as possible on the next business day.

A user name, e-mail address, and password are required to post comments and your comments will be associated with your user name. Comments are powered by a 3rd party service called [ Disqus ](http://disqus.com/) .   [ Disqus also has a privacy policy that you can review ](http://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/466259-privacy-policy) .

To protect your privacy, please do not include information (e.g., an e-mail address or phone number) in the text of your comment that identifies you.

## Site Security

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, our website hosting platform system employ software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.

Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Raw data logs are used for no other purposes and are scheduled for regular destruction in accordance with National Archives and Records Administration guidelines.

Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act.

## External Links

Nationalpriorities.org may contain links to websites created and maintained by other public and/or private organizations. Nationalpriorities.org provides these links as a service to our users. When users link to an outside website, they are leaving the nationalpriorities.org site and are subject to the privacy and security policies of the owners/sponsors of the outside website(s). You are encouraged to familiarize yourself with these policies.

## Changes to this Policy

The nationalpriorities.org privacy policy will be revised or updated if practices change, or if better ways to keep you informed are developed. You should refer to this page often for the latest information and the effective date of any changes. If changes are made to this policy, a new policy will be posted on our site and the date at the bottom of the page will be updated. Changes to the policy will not apply retroactively.

If you have any questions or concerns, please  contact us.
